### LEON MALISOV

PHONE: (347) 840-2712

E-MAIL: leonmalisov@gmail.com

WEBSITE: websquisher.com

### **ABOUT ME:**

Self-taught web developer with a deep understanding of front-end languages like HTML & CSS, JS, and React and back-end technologies like PostgreSQL and Firebase. Expert learner and team player with experience building fast, beautiful and responsive sites.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

Freelance Web Developer

June 2019 - Present

- Built and deployed a fully functional React ecommerce app from scratch
- Completed several highly-ranked Udemy courses on advanced JavaScript and React concepts

### Paper Jam Tutoring, New York, NY

Sep 2016 – Present

Founder

- Provide comprehensive instruction to undergraduate students in Business and English
- Work with clients to create individualized organizational plans geared toward academic success
- Mentor underperforming students in my neighborhood.

Feb 2019 - Dec 2019 Home Health Aide

- Tailored and implemented client's post-stroke rehabilitation program
- Supervised client's safety and health while encouraging mental and physical self-challenge

## Bentley Hotel, New York, NY

Aug 2016 - Dec 2016

Front Desk Associate

- Played a key role in managing guest relationships, including post-stay outreach
- Managed a rapidly-changing schedule of over one hundred hotel rooms at full capacity
- Handled a wide range of personal services, including concierge services

## Keystone Equities, LLC, New York, NY

June 2016 – Aug 2016

Market Research Intern

- Compiled detailed reports on dozens of primary U.S. real estate markets
- Prepared in-depth presentation materials on U.S. markets for prospective clients.
- Worked closely with a large office-sharing client to identify prospective opportunities for expansion

# Thomson Reuters Foundation, London

Sep 2015 - Dec 2015

Media Development Intern

- Created, populated and maintained a database of hundreds of media consultants
- Contributed stories to the foundation's Africa desk on under-reported news
- Participated in C-level corporate communication training programs

### Franklin & Marshall Martin Library of the Sciences, Lancaster, PA

Spring 2014 – Spring 2015

- Archived collections of rare materials donated to F&M college
- Assisted students and faculty with administrative tasks and research queries

# **EDUCATION:**

# Franklin & Marshall College, Lancaster, PA

May 2018

Business Management major

## **SKILLS:**

Archivist

Web: React, JavaScript, Node.js, HTML & CSS, Git, Firebase, Google Analytics.

Language: English native, fluent in Russian, elementary proficiency in Hebrew and French

Other: Corporate accounting, Microsoft Excel, Word, PowerPoint

### **OTHER ACTIVITIES:**

Head of international news at F&M Business Club, F&M Model UN, F&M rowing team